<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>DevOps - Category - Boyang Yan's Tech Blog</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/categories/devops/</link><description>DevOps - Category - Boyang Yan's Tech Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</managingEditor><webMaster>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 11:18:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yanboyang.com/categories/devops/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>DevOps Beginner's Guide</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/devops/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 11:18:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/devops/</guid><description><![CDATA[Overview In this blog, I discussed what is DevOps, and why it has gained so much traction in the IT industry lately.
What Is DevOps? It is a combination of practices that streamline the automation and integration of processes between the software development and IT teams. This will help them to build, test, and release software in a faster and more reliable way.
Purpose The term was formed by combining the words &ldquo;development&rdquo; and &ldquo;operations&rdquo; and signifies a cultural shift that helps bridge the gap between the development and operation teams.]]></description></item><item><title>Terraform Beginner's Guide</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/terraform/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 11:09:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/terraform/</guid><description>Overview In this blog post, I am going to cover a brief introduction of Infrastructure as Code (IaC), Terraform, its lifecycle, and all the core concepts that every beginner should know. I have tried to cover all the topics in this beginner’s guide that will give you a quick start for using Terraform.
Prerequires What Is Infrastructure as Code (IaC)? What Is Terraform? Terraform Lifecycle Terraform Core Concepts Terraform Installation Terraform Providers Terraform Configuration Files Getting started using Terraform Import Existing Infrastructure Conclusion Related/References</description></item><item><title>The comparison and introduction between Terraform and Ansible</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/terraformandansible/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 10:53:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/terraformandansible/</guid><description>Overview The Terraform vs. Ansible battle continues to escalate as the DevOps environment focuses more on automation and orchestration. These two tools help in automating configurations and deploying infrastructure. Terraform offers to deploy Infrastructure as a Code, helps in readability and lift and shift deployments. Ansible is a configuration management tool for automating system configuration and management.
Terraform What is Terraform? Terraform is an open-source tool for building, changing, and versioning infrastructure securely and effectively.</description></item></channel></rss>