<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0"><channel><title>DevOps - Category - Boyang Yan's Tech Blog</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/categories/devops/</link><description>DevOps - Category - Boyang Yan's Tech Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</managingEditor><webMaster>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 17:39:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yanboyang.com/categories/devops/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Install Terrafom with Quick start tutorial</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/terraforminstall/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 17:39:00 +0800</pubDate><author>yanboyang713@gmail.com</author><dc:creator>Boyang Yan</dc:creator><guid>https://yanboyang.com/terraforminstall/</guid><description><![CDATA[Pre-reading DevOps/DevOps Beginner&amp;rsquo;s Guide DevOps/Terraform Beginner&amp;rsquo;s Guide DevOps/The comparison and introduction between Terraform and Ansible Install Arch Linux 1 yay -S terraform Ubuntu/Debian Ensure that your system is up to date, and you have the gnupg, software-properties-common, and curl packages installed. You will use these packages to verify HashiCorp&rsquo;s GPG signature, and install HashiCorp&rsquo;s Debian package repository.
1 sudo apt-get update &amp;&amp; sudo apt-get install -y gnupg software-properties-common curl Add the HashiCorp GPG key.]]></description></item><item><title>Ansible Beginner's Guide</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/ansible/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 17:58:00 +0800</pubDate><author>yanboyang713@gmail.com</author><dc:creator>Boyang Yan</dc:creator><guid>https://yanboyang.com/ansible/</guid><description>Overview This article covers all the aspects of Ansible, a tool used in DevOps for the Management, Deployment, and Orchestration of IT Infrastructure.
What Is Ansible? Ansible is a simple configuration management and IT automation engine for multi-tier deployments. It automates both cloud and on-premise provisioning &amp;amp; configuration. It automates cloud provisioning. Rather than managing one system at a time, Ansible uses a model that inter-relates the entire IT infrastructure and enables you to manage everything using something called an Infrastructure as Code (IAC) approach.</description></item><item><title>DevOps Beginner's Guide</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/devops/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 11:18:00 +0800</pubDate><author>yanboyang713@gmail.com</author><dc:creator>Boyang Yan</dc:creator><guid>https://yanboyang.com/devops/</guid><description><![CDATA[Overview In this blog, I discussed what is DevOps, and why it has gained so much traction in the IT industry lately.
What Is DevOps? It is a combination of practices that streamline the automation and integration of processes between the software development and IT teams. This will help them to build, test, and release software in a faster and more reliable way.
Purpose The term was formed by combining the words &ldquo;development&rdquo; and &ldquo;operations&rdquo; and signifies a cultural shift that helps bridge the gap between the development and operation teams.]]></description></item><item><title>Terraform Beginner's Guide</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/terraform/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 11:09:00 +0800</pubDate><author>yanboyang713@gmail.com</author><dc:creator>Boyang Yan</dc:creator><guid>https://yanboyang.com/terraform/</guid><description>Overview In this blog post, I am going to cover a brief introduction of Infrastructure as Code (IaC), Terraform, its lifecycle, and all the core concepts that every beginner should know. I have tried to cover all the topics in this beginner’s guide that will give you a quick start for using Terraform.
Prerequires 1. DevOps/DevOps Beginner&amp;amp;rsquo;s Guide What Is Infrastructure as Code (IaC)? Infrastructure as Code (IaC) is a widespread terminology among DevOps professionals and a key DevOps practice in the industry.</description></item><item><title>The comparison and introduction between Terraform and Ansible</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/terraformandansible/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 10:53:00 +0800</pubDate><author>yanboyang713@gmail.com</author><dc:creator>Boyang Yan</dc:creator><guid>https://yanboyang.com/terraformandansible/</guid><description>Overview The Terraform vs. Ansible battle continues to escalate as the DevOps environment focuses more on automation and orchestration. These two tools help in automating configurations and deploying infrastructure. Terraform offers to deploy Infrastructure as a Code, helps in readability and lift and shift deployments. Ansible is a configuration management tool for automating system configuration and management.
Terraform What is Terraform? Terraform is an open-source tool for building, changing, and versioning infrastructure securely and effectively.</description></item></channel></rss>