<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>terraform - Tag - Boyang Yan's Tech Blog</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/tags/terraform/</link><description>terraform - Tag - Boyang Yan's Tech Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</managingEditor><webMaster>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 17:39:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yanboyang.com/tags/terraform/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Install Terrafom with Quick start tutorial</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/terraforminstall/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 17:39:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/terraforminstall/</guid><description><![CDATA[Pre-reading  DevOps/DevOps Beginner&rsquo;s Guide DevOps/Terraform Beginner&rsquo;s Guide DevOps/The comparison and introduction between Terraform and Ansible  Install Arch Linux 1  yay -S terraform   Ubuntu/Debian Ensure that your system is up to date, and you have the gnupg, software-properties-common, and curl packages installed. You will use these packages to verify HashiCorp&rsquo;s GPG signature, and install HashiCorp&rsquo;s Debian package repository.
1  sudo apt-get update &amp;&amp; sudo apt-get install -y gnupg software-properties-common curl   Add the HashiCorp GPG key.]]></description></item><item><title>Terraform Beginner's Guide</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/terraform/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 11:09:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/terraform/</guid><description>Overview In this blog post, I am going to cover a brief introduction of Infrastructure as Code (IaC), Terraform, its lifecycle, and all the core concepts that every beginner should know. I have tried to cover all the topics in this beginner’s guide that will give you a quick start for using Terraform.
Prerequires 1.DevOps/DevOps Beginner&amp;rsquo;s Guide
What Is Infrastructure as Code (IaC)? Infrastructure as Code (IaC) is a widespread terminology among DevOps professionals and a key DevOps practice in the industry.</description></item><item><title>The comparison and introduction between Terraform and Ansible</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/terraformandansible/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 10:53:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/terraformandansible/</guid><description>Overview The Terraform vs. Ansible battle continues to escalate as the DevOps environment focuses more on automation and orchestration. These two tools help in automating configurations and deploying infrastructure. Terraform offers to deploy Infrastructure as a Code, helps in readability and lift and shift deployments. Ansible is a configuration management tool for automating system configuration and management.
Terraform What is Terraform? Terraform is an open-source tool for building, changing, and versioning infrastructure securely and effectively.</description></item><item><title>Build a Kubernetes cluster on Proxmox via Ansible and Terraform</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/k8sonproxmox/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 20:27:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/k8sonproxmox/</guid><description>Overview Proxmox is an open-source hypervisor that have enterprise capabilities and a large community behind it.
For Terraform and Ansible, I always like the idea of infrastructure as code (iac) and Terraform and Ansible just make it easy to accomplish.
The idea here was to be able to spin up a k3s cluster with minimum effort so I can spin it up and down for ever project that I would like to run.</description></item></channel></rss>