<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Boyang Yan's Tech Blog</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/</link><description>This is Boyang Yan's Tech Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</managingEditor><webMaster>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 17:30:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yanboyang.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Home Manager using Nix</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/nixhomemanager/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 17:30:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/nixhomemanager/</guid><description>Home Manager Standalone installation Add the appropriate Home Manager channel. If you are following Nixpkgs master or an unstable channel you can run.
1 2 nix-channel --add https://github.com/nix-community/home-manager/archive/master.tar.gz home-manager nix-channel --update 1 2 cat ~/.nix-channels nix-channel --list Check your echo $NIX_PATH, If your have NOT
you may have to add
1 2 3 4 5 6 export NIX_PATH=$HOME/.nix-defexpr/channels${NIX_PATH:+:}$NIX_PATH /nix/var/nix/profiles/per-user/yanboyang713/channels export NIX_PATH=nixpkgs=/nix/var/nix/profiles/per-user/yanboyang713/channels/nixpkgs:/nix/var/nix/profiles/per-user/yanboyang713/channels:~/.nix-defexpr/channels to your shell</description></item><item><title>Nix Installation</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/nixinstallation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 15:18:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/nixinstallation/</guid><description>Supported Platforms Nix is currently supported on the following platforms:
Linux (i686, x86_64, aarch64). macOS (x86_64). Installing a Binary Distribution We recommend the multi-user install if it supports your platform and you can authenticate with sudo.
Single User Installation To explicitly select a single-user installation on your system:
1 sh &amp;lt;(curl -L https://nixos.org/nix/install) --no-daemon This will perform a single-user installation of Nix, meaning that /nix is owned by the invoking user.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started with Nix</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/nix/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2021 12:34:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/nix/</guid><description>Introduction The NixOS package manager is a system of its own. You can use it under any Linux Distribution.
What does NixOS Package Manager do? Most package managers use a file that contains the executable or source code. They then calculate what it needs on the system and then make sure that it exists. In Nix, things work very similarly. The big difference is that Nix creates all the files, and compiles them if necessary, then put them in one place; the nix-store.</description></item><item><title>VIM Keyboard Shortcuts Cheatsheet</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/vim/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 16:16:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/vim/</guid><description>Introduction This post document is brief introduction about how to use VIM/VI text editor and help you remember the shortcuts. The Vim editor is a command-line based tool that’s an enhanced version of the venerable vi editor. Despite the abundance of graphical rich text editors, familiarity with Vim will help every Linux user – from an experienced system administrator to a newbie Raspberry Pi user.
One important thing to note when using Vim, is that the function of a key depends on the &amp;ldquo;mode&amp;rdquo; the editor is in.</description></item><item><title>Arch Linux/Manjaro sound and sound card configuration</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/configsound/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 19:04:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/configsound/</guid><description>Introduction After install Arch Linux/Manjaro, although alsa-utils has been installed, it may still not play sound correctly. Here is a solution.
First try 1 amixer sset Master unmute If you use alsamixer to unmute the master sound, you still can&amp;rsquo;t play the sound.
Please, following the steps at the below.
NOTE: If you faced maixer: Unable to find simple cintrol &amp;lsquo;Master&amp;rsquo;, 0, that means, it maybe that the sound card device cannot be found or the sound card driver us not installed.</description></item><item><title>Virtualize Windows 11 with Proxmox</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/windows11pve/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 12:37:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/windows11pve/</guid><description><![CDATA[Introduction As Microsoft released Windows 11, it was made clear that TPM 2.0 and Secure boot is no longer optional but mandatory, without these capabilities on the hardware/virtual hardware, Windows 11 refuse to install.
Step 1: Download Windows 11 ISO You can click Here for download ISO file.
Step 2: Download virtio-win drivers disk You can click Here, download Latest virtio-win ISO.
Step 3: Upload Windows 11 ISO and Latest virtio-win ISO to ProxMox login to ProxMox -&gt; choose Node -&gt; local (pve) -&gt; ISO Images -&gt; Upload]]></description></item><item><title>Managing Your Dotfiles With Git and Make</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/dotfiles/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 18:59:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/dotfiles/</guid><description>Introduction User-specific application configuration is traditionally stored in so called dotfiles (files whose filename starts with a dot). It is common practice to track dotfiles with a version control system such as Git to keep track of changes and synchronize dotfiles across various hosts. There are various approaches to managing your dotfiles. In this article, I will talk about How to use Make with Git to management your dotfiles and package.</description></item><item><title>Install Terrafom with Quick start tutorial</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/terraforminstall/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 17:39:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/terraforminstall/</guid><description><![CDATA[Pre-reading  DevOps/DevOps Beginner&rsquo;s Guide DevOps/Terraform Beginner&rsquo;s Guide DevOps/The comparison and introduction between Terraform and Ansible  Install Arch Linux 1  yay -S terraform   Ubuntu/Debian Ensure that your system is up to date, and you have the gnupg, software-properties-common, and curl packages installed. You will use these packages to verify HashiCorp&rsquo;s GPG signature, and install HashiCorp&rsquo;s Debian package repository.
1  sudo apt-get update &amp;&amp; sudo apt-get install -y gnupg software-properties-common curl   Add the HashiCorp GPG key.]]></description></item><item><title>Using Emacs Org-Babel Mode to Write Literate Programming Documents</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/orgbabel/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 10:29:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/orgbabel/</guid><description>Introduction We introduce the use of emacs org-babel model in this document. Emacs Org-Babel mode is a literate programming tool (aka. active document), which can embed multiple programming languages, inlcuding R, Python, C/C++ in one document. Babel has ability to execute source code within Org-mode documents.
Pre-reading Emacs/Getting Started Org-mode on Emacs Source Code Insert &amp;amp; Running Here is an format example:
1 2 #+BEGIN_SRC language #+END_SRC Reference List https://orgmode.</description></item><item><title>Best practices for using Emacs org-mode as a day-planner/scheduler/calendar</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/orgplanning/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 18:28:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/orgplanning/</guid><description>Pre-reading Emacs/Getting Started Org-mode on Emacs Checkbox It often great to split a task into a number of simple steps. Or you can use them in a shopping list.
The form is [], put in front of the task can mark the completion status of the task, Put it after the task to mark the completion degree of the task, which needs to add % or /
Here is an example of a checkbox list.</description></item></channel></rss>