<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Boyang Yan's Tech Blog</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/</link><description>This is Boyang Yan's Tech Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</managingEditor><webMaster>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 19:27:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yanboyang.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Change the Suckless DWM Wallpaper with Feh</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/dwmwallpaper/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 19:27:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/dwmwallpaper/</guid><description>Introduction By default DWM does NOT have a background and it does NOT have a background manager like you would find in Gnome or KDE or other full desktop environments.
DWM it is very easy to set a background using a small program called Feh. So, Let&amp;rsquo;s we begin.
Installation Firstly, we need to install Feh.
1 yay -S feh Usage 1 feh --bg-fill Arch-Linux-blue-desktop-kiss-Linux-logo-nice-wallpaper-1657915.png Now, it just updated my Wallpaper.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started Xorg with display manager</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/xorg/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 14:00:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/xorg/</guid><description>Introduction Pre-reading WM/Getting Started Display Server compared with X11, Wayland and Mir Install Xorg 1 pacman -S xorg-server xorg-xinit xorg-xrandr xorg-xsetroot Installing a Display Manager (DM) 1 2 3 4 5 pacman -S lightdm pacman -S lightdm-gtk-greeter pacman -S lightdm-gtk-greeter-settings Enable lightdm service 1 sudo systemctl enable lightdm xinit The xinit program allows a user to manually start an Xorg display server.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started Display Server compared with X11, Wayland and Mir</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/displayserver/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 13:08:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/displayserver/</guid><description>Introduction In Linux related articles, news and discussions, you’ll often come across the term display server, Xorg, Wayland etc.
What is display server in Linux? A display server is a program which is responsible for the input and output coordination of its clients, to and from the rest of the operating system, and among the hardware and the operating system.
Basically, thanks to a display server, you can use your computer graphically (GUI).</description></item><item><title>Picom: A lightweight compositor for X11</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/picom/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 14:03:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/picom/</guid><description>picom picom is a standalone compositor for Xorg, suitable for use with window managers that do not provide compositing. picom is a fork of compton, which is a fork of xcompmgr-dana, which in turn is a fork of xcompmgr.
1 yay -S picom</description></item><item><title>Multi Monitor SetUp</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/multimonitor/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 13:59:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/multimonitor/</guid><description>Multi-monitor setup If configured to use Xinerama libraries in config.mk, dwm can automatically detect configured screen outputs (monitor, overhead projector, etc.) and their resolutions and draw the windows in the output area accordingly.
One of the easiest ways to configure screen outputs is via the RandR X server extension using the xrandr tool. Without arguments it will list the current configuration of screen outputs.
1 xrandr For each connected output the supported resolution modes will be printed.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started DWM's Status Monitor</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/dwmstatusmonitor/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 13:55:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/dwmstatusmonitor/</guid><description>Introduction A modular statusbar for dwm written in C. You may think of it as i3blocks, but for dwm.
Pre-reading WM/Getting Started Dynamic Window Manager (DWM) Features Modular Lightweight Suckless Blocks are clickable Blocks are loaded asynchronously Each block can be externally triggered to update itself Compatible with i3blocks scripts Why dwmblocks? In dwm, you have to set the statusbar through an infinite loop like this:</description></item><item><title>Getting Started Slock</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/slock/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 13:50:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/slock/</guid><description><![CDATA[Introduction slock Simple X display locker. This is the simplest X screen locker we are aware of.
1 2  git clone https://git.suckless.org/slock cd slock   Before, your sudo make install You need
1  vim config.def.h   change to
1 2 3  /* user and group to drop privileges to */ static const char *user = &#34;yanboyang713&#34;; static const char *group = &#34;yanboyang713&#34;;   slock: getgrnam nogroup: group entry not found]]></description></item><item><title>How to management patches in DWM</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/dwmpatches/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 13:50:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/dwmpatches/</guid><description>Introduction DWM only have less than 2000 lines of code. If you want to add more functionality for your DWM you need patches.
There are two types of patches:
The ones that fit to your personal taste The ones you think should be included in mainline. There are also have TWO patch methods.
Manual patches Using DWM Flexipatch (recommend) Pre-reading WM/Getting Started Dynamic Window Manager (DWM) Manual patches patch filename format The expected format for patches is:</description></item><item><title>Create Github Profile based on README</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/githubprofile/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 11:52:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/githubprofile/</guid><description>Introduction If you visit other peoples GitHub profiles, some people have some fancy pictures, descriptions and stats in their profiles. These are the new GitHub Profile README. They are kind of a hidden new feature and in this article I will show you how to create one and how make it stand out using some cool tricks and tools!
First Step: Crate new Github repository You should create a new repository, which name should same as your GitHub&amp;rsquo;s Username.</description></item><item><title>An introduction for Git</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/git/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 12:09:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/git/</guid><description>Git Cli Install If you facing this ERROR message (bash: gh: command not found), please following this document installing gh on your Linux first. Below section, I will tell you how to use Make to management your package.
1 sudo pacman -S github-cli Login Step1:
1 2 3 4 [yanboyang713@Boyang-PC dotfiles]$ gh auth login ? What account do you want to log into? [Use arrows to move, type to filter] &amp;gt; GitHub.</description></item></channel></rss>