<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Boyang Yan's Tech Blog</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/</link><description>This is Boyang Yan's Tech Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</managingEditor><webMaster>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 18:28:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yanboyang.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Best practices for using Emacs org-mode as a day-planner/scheduler/calendar</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/orgplanning/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 18:28:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/orgplanning/</guid><description>Pre-reading Emacs/Getting Started Org-mode on Emacs Checkbox It often great to split a task into a number of simple steps. Or you can use them in a shopping list.
The form is [], put in front of the task can mark the completion status of the task, Put it after the task to mark the completion degree of the task, which needs to add % or /
Here is an example of a checkbox list.</description></item><item><title>Verify Your Site For Bing Webmaster Tools - Bing SEO</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/bingseo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 20:22:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/bingseo/</guid><description>Introduction Bing Webmaster Tools optimizes your site and monitors its performance in Bing search engine results.
You should verify your site with Bing Webmaster Tools after launching your site.
Before you start, create a Microsoft account.
Steps
Log in to Bing with with your Microsoft Account. Under My Sites, enter your site&amp;rsquo;s URL. Click Add. On the Add a site page, in Add a sitemap, enter http://yoursite.com/sitemap%5Findex.xml. Optionally select the time of day when you anticipate the most traffic to your site, then click Add.</description></item><item><title>Verify Your Site For Baidu Webmaster Tools - Baidu SEO</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/baiduseo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 13:13:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/baiduseo/</guid><description>Introduction Baidu Webmaster Tools, or Baidu Ziyuan, is a resource platform that tracks and enhances your site’s organic performance on Baidu, China’s #1 search engine with 222+ million active users.
In addition to enabling faster mobile indexation on Baidu and improved monitoring of your site’s crawlability, Baidu Ziyuan (Baidu Webmaster Tools) identifies and recommends critical SEO best practices and solutions unique to your site to improve your visibility on the most-used search engine in China: Baidu.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started Org-mode on Emacs</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/org-mode/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 11:29:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/org-mode/</guid><description>Introduction Org mode is an artifact under Emacs. Compared with the lightweight format of markdown, It has more functions and expandability, but it is still difficult to get started. Here is only a brief introduction to some of the basic functions.
Pre-reading Emacs/Getting Started with Doom Emacs :Emacs:Doom-Emacs: Fundamental Feature Headings org-mode uses * to indicate headings, and the number of * to indicate heading level:
1 2 3 * First level heading ** Secondary heading *** Level 3 heading Use the Control-[RET] key to insert the title of the same level, and you can use the Alt-left/right title to increase and decrease the level Using Alt-Up and Alt-Down swap the Headings content Up and Down (including sub-chapters).</description></item><item><title>Creating a Hugo blog</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/hugo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 17:31:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/hugo/</guid><description>Overview This is a tutorial on creating a blog or website using hugo (a static site generator).
We will use Docker as our development environment. Also, we will storge our Hugo development code in Github main branche and automate the whole process with Github Action Workflow for Github Pages.
Prerequisites You will need to have the following:
Docker installation. Docker is available for Mac/Windows/Linux and is easily installed. You can following the link at the below for install Docker.</description></item><item><title>Exporting Org Roam notes to hugo :hugo:org-roam:</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/roamtohugo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 13:20:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/roamtohugo/</guid><description>Introduction Pre-reading Read this article: Blog/Creating a Hugo blog and Set-up your HUGO blog References https://sidhartharya.me/exporting-org-roam-notes-to-hugo/</description></item><item><title>Creating ProxMox templates with packer</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/packer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 12:08:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/packer/</guid><description>Introduction With proxmox when can create templates for our VMS so we can have a standard starting point to install our applications on top of, these templates can be useful too so that you can pre-install packages for authentication, security, logging and etc without anyone else needing to think about it.
However, creating and managing these templates can become a challenge with how time-consuming and manual it can be. I want to show you how you can make this process more standardized and automated with the use of packer to allow you to declare your proxmox templates as code.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started IpTV with RouterOS and OpenVswitch</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/iptv/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 19:52:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/iptv/</guid><description>After replacing the optical modem with the optical module, it is found that there are vlan 3964 and 4000, and there are igmp data on them, you can watch iptv through igmp proxy.
The specific operation method is as follows:
Interface–&amp;gt;Add a VLAN virtual interface to the sfp optical port, with any Name and VLAN ID=4000. Not necessarily 4000 in other regions Randomly configure an IP address for the VLAN4000 virtual interface.</description></item><item><title>Configuring Network Bonding</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/bonding/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 17:57:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/bonding/</guid><description>Introduction Network bonding refers to the combination of network interfaces on one host for redundancy and/or increased throughput.
Redundancy is the key factor: we want to protect our virtualized environment from loss of service due to failure of a single physical link. This network bonding is the same as the Linux network bonding.
Using network bonding in OpenVswitch OVS require some switch configuration.
In this article, I will demonstrate How to use Networking Bonding between OVSBridge and Ubiquiti.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started OpenWrt</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/openwrt/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 11:42:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/openwrt/</guid><description>Introduction The OpenWrt Project is a Linux operating system targeting embedded devices. Instead of trying to create a single, static firmware, OpenWrt provides a fully writable filesystem with package management. This frees you from the application selection and configuration provided by the vendor and allows you to customize the device through the use of packages to suit any application.
OpenWrt official Website Here.
In this article, I will talk about:</description></item></channel></rss>