<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Boyang Yan's Tech Blog</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/</link><description>This is Boyang Yan's Tech Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</managingEditor><webMaster>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 17:50:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yanboyang.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Getting Started Dynamic Window Manager (DWM)</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/dwm/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 17:50:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/dwm/</guid><description><![CDATA[Introduction Installing Install Xorg 1  pacman -S xorg-server xorg-xinit xorg-xrandr xorg-xsetroot   Install DWM 1 2 3  git clone git://git.suckless.org/dwm ~/.config/dwm git clone git://git.suckless.org/st ~/.config/st git clone git://git.suckless.org/dmenu ~/.config/dmenu   1 2 3  cd ~/.config/dwm &amp;&amp; sudo make install cd ~/.config/st &amp;&amp; sudo make install cd ~/.config/dmenu &amp;&amp; sudo make install   Installing a Display Manager (DM) 1 2 3 4 5  pacman -S lightdm pacman -S lightdm-gtk-greeter pacman -S lightdm-gtk-greeter-settings   Enable lightdm service 1  sudo systemctl enable lightdm   Adding an entry for DWM in the DM Create this file and add the following.]]></description></item><item><title>Gettting Started SRS(Simple Realtime Server)</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/srs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 11:43:00 +1100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/srs/</guid><description>Overview SRS is a simple, high efficiency and realtime video server, supports RTMP/WebRTC/HLS/HTTP-FLV/SRT.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started Configuring VLANs on Proxmox</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/vlan/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 19:52:00 +1100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/vlan/</guid><description>Introduction A virtualization server allows you to run multiple machines, virtual machines (VMs), on one physical device, also known as the host. There could be many different VMs each for different tasks. In this guide, we will discuss configuring your Proxmox virtualization server to use VLANs so that you can group related VMs onto their own subnet.
Motivation For security, as well as organizational purposes, physical machines are often separated on the network from each other by VLANs.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started ROS and Openwrt with Proxmox</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/rosandopenwrtproxmox/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 19:52:00 +1100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/rosandopenwrtproxmox/</guid><description>Install Open vSwitch Update the package index and then install the Open vSwitch packages by executing:
1 2 3 apt update apt install ifupdown2 apt install openvswitch-switch root@pve-home:~# cat etc/network/interfaces https://karneliuk.com/2021/08/infrastructure-1-building-virtualized-environment-with-debian-linux-and-proxmox-on-hp-and-supermicro
ifreload -a ifup vmbr0
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 auto lo iface lo inet loopback auto enp6s0 iface enp6s0 inet manual auto enp1s0 iface enp1s0 inet manual auto enp2s0 iface enp2s0 inet manual auto enp3s0 iface enp3s0 inet manual auto enp5s0 iface enp5s0 inet manual auto ens9 iface ens9 inet manual auto vlan1 iface vlan1 inet static address 192.</description></item><item><title>Beginning Explore artificial intelligence and computer vision</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/firstexploreaiandcomputervision/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 19:17:00 +1100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/firstexploreaiandcomputervision/</guid><description>What is artificial intelligence? Explore into artificial intelligence For the definition of artificial intelligence, academic research area always have different understandings. The widely accepted definition is:
Artificial intelligence is the use of machines to simulate human cognitive abilities technology. Artificial intelligence involves a wide range of insights, learning, reasoning and decision-making.
From the perspective of industry application, the core ability of artificial intelligence ability is to make judgments or predictions based on given input.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started with Doom Emacs</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/doom/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 03:44:00 +1100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/doom/</guid><description>Prerequisites Instation Arch Linux 1 2 3 4 5 6 # required dependencies pacman -S git emacs ripgrep # optional dependencies pacman -S fd yay -S emacs-pdf-tools-git ``` With Emacs and Doom’s dependencies installed, next is to install Doom Emacs itself:
1 2 git clone https://github.com/hlissner/doom-emacs ~/.emacs.d ~/.emacs.d/bin/doom install Sart-up https://zzamboni.org/post/my-doom-emacs-configuration-with-commentary/
Install the icons to avoid having weird symbols. M-x all-the-icons-install-fonts
Note: M-x is SPC :</description></item><item><title>An introduction for Git</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/git/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 06:11:32 +1000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/git/</guid><description>Git Cli Install If you facing this ERROR message (bash: gh: command not found), please following this document installing gh on your Linux first. Below section, I will tell you how to use Make to management your package.
1 sudo pacman -S github-cli Login Step1:
1 2 3 4 [yanboyang713@Boyang-PC dotfiles]$ gh auth login ? What account do you want to log into? [Use arrows to move, type to filter] &amp;gt; GitHub.</description></item><item><title>Managing Your Dotfiles With Git and Make</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/dotfiles/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 06:11:32 +1000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/dotfiles/</guid><description>Introduction User-specific application configuration is traditionally stored in so called dotfiles (files whose filename starts with a dot). It is common practice to track dotfiles with a version control system such as Git to keep track of changes and synchronize dotfiles across various hosts. There are various approaches to managing your dotfiles. In this article, I will talk about How to use Make with Git to management your dotfiles and package.</description></item><item><title>Beginners Guide to Ham Radio</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/ham/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 06:11:32 +1000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/ham/</guid><description>Coaxial Cable http://www.m5bxb.com/coaxlengthcalc.htm Connector https://shop33395161.taobao.com/p/rd262982.htm https://shop33395161.taobao.com/p/rd770430.htm
Dummy load vector network analyzer</description></item><item><title>Getting Started with Emacs</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/emacs/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 06:11:32 +1000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/emacs/</guid><description>Installation Run Emacs in Docker https://github.com/Silex/docker-emacs
Usage Console 1 docker run -it --rm silex/emacs GUI 1 2 xhost +local:root # WARN: this comes with security issues docker run -it --rm -e DISPLAY -v /tmp/.X11-unix:/tmp/.X11-unix silex/emacs Arch Linux (Manjaro) 1 yay -S emacs macOS Prerequisites 1 2 # Installs clang xcode-select --install emacs-mac. It offers good integration with macOS, native emojis and better childframe support 1 2 3 brew tap railwaycat/emacsmacport brew install emacs-mac --with-modules ln -s /usr/local/opt/emacs-mac/Emacs.</description></item></channel></rss>