<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Boyang Yan's Tech Blog</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/</link><description>This is Boyang Yan's Tech Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</managingEditor><webMaster>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 15:25:00 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yanboyang.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Getting Started Creating Arch Linux packages</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/creatingarchlinuxpackages/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 15:25:00 +1000</pubDate><author>yanboyang713@gmail.com</author><dc:creator>Boyang Yan</dc:creator><guid>https://yanboyang.com/creatingarchlinuxpackages/</guid><description>Introduction This article aims to assist users creating their own packages using the Arch Linux &amp;ldquo;ports-like&amp;rdquo; build system. It covers creation of a PKGBUILD – a package build description file sourced by makepkg to create a binary package from source. If already in possession of a PKGBUILD, see makepkg. For instructions regarding existing rules and ways to improve package quality see Arch packaging standards.</description></item><item><title>Models for Stationary Time Series</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/stationarytimeseries/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 16:18:00 +1100</pubDate><author>yanboyang713@gmail.com</author><dc:creator>Boyang Yan</dc:creator><guid>https://yanboyang.com/stationarytimeseries/</guid><description>Introduction We will focus on general linear processes, moving average processes, autoregressive processes, the mixed Autoregressive Moving Average (ARMA) models and invertibility. These concepts provide the required basis for one of the frequently used ARMA methodology. We will have hands-on tasks to deepen your understanding of ARMA models and improve your skillsets for the implementation of time series analysis methods.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started Custom Arch Linux Package Repository with GitHub</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/archlinuxpackagerepository/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 18:43:00 +1100</pubDate><author>yanboyang713@gmail.com</author><dc:creator>Boyang Yan</dc:creator><guid>https://yanboyang.com/archlinuxpackagerepository/</guid><description>Introduction I am making a Arch Linux based Meta Scientific Linux,so I need create a custom Package Repository for this OS packages.
In this article, I’m going to record my steps to create my own arch linux package repository, via github pages, no need to maintain your server.
Build signed packages Create your gpg key When you installed a package from AUR, you generally cloned a repo that contains a PKGBUILD file, then you executed makepkg to build this package.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started Magit on Doom Emacs</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/magit/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 12:58:00 +1100</pubDate><author>yanboyang713@gmail.com</author><dc:creator>Boyang Yan</dc:creator><guid>https://yanboyang.com/magit/</guid><description>Introduction This article is intended as a quick and dirty reference for the &amp;ldquo;Magit&amp;rdquo; Git interface in Doom Emacs.
Magit is arguably the best Git tool out there and also my favorite. It is a package in Emacs, and it is text based.
Commands Initialize create a Git Repository from a floder
1 SPC g i or,
1 M-x magit-init Navigate to the Magit Window:
1 SPC-g-g or C-x g staged and unstaged Add all of files to staged</description></item><item><title>Getting started with Simulation of Urban Mobility (SUMO)</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/gettingwithsumo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 16:15:00 +1100</pubDate><author>yanboyang713@gmail.com</author><dc:creator>Boyang Yan</dc:creator><guid>https://yanboyang.com/gettingwithsumo/</guid><description>Introduction The Simulation of Urban Mobility (SUMO) platform is an open source platform that enables simulation of traffic flows in complex environments. There aren’t many tutorials I’ve come across that teach you how to create a complex traffic simulation from start to finish.
Installation There are multiple ways to install SUMO , but I prefer the pip install way, that installs SUMO as well as the python libraries to interface with SUMO.</description></item><item><title>Analysis of Trends</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/analysisoftrends/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 00:04:00 +1100</pubDate><author>yanboyang713@gmail.com</author><dc:creator>Boyang Yan</dc:creator><guid>https://yanboyang.com/analysisoftrends/</guid><description>Introduction We will study trend models for the analysis of time series data. Trend models that we will cover include linear, quadratic and harmonic trend models and those account for seasonality. We will observe that while the trend models are very good at capturing the trend in time series data, their performance is poor on capturing serial correlation in time series data. We will have hands-on tasks to deepen your understanding of trend models and improve your skillsets for the implementation of time series analysis methods.</description></item><item><title>Time Series Analysis Basic Plots, Examples, and Fundamental Concepts</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/timeseriesanalysisweek1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 18:23:00 +1100</pubDate><author>yanboyang713@gmail.com</author><dc:creator>Boyang Yan</dc:creator><guid>https://yanboyang.com/timeseriesanalysisweek1/</guid><description>Introduction You will study the basic context of time series and stochastic processes including basic visualisations for time series data.
Time series data is composed of observations collected sequentially over time. This type of data is frequently seen and analysed in data analytics applications.
In business, we observe
weekly interest rates, daily closing stock prices, monthly price indices, yearly sales figures, and so forth. In meteorology, we observe
daily high and low temperatures, annual precipitation and drought indices, and hourly wind speeds.</description></item><item><title>Making Slideshows From Emacs Org Mode with org-reveal</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/revealslides/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 17:00:00 +1100</pubDate><author>yanboyang713@gmail.com</author><dc:creator>Boyang Yan</dc:creator><guid>https://yanboyang.com/revealslides/</guid><description><![CDATA[Introduction In this article, I will talk about How to using Emacs with org-reveal to make a slideshows. This article will based on Jake &rsquo;s video in YouTube.
Doom Emacs Set-up Setting up org-reveal within Doom Emacs is straightforward.
Add these lines to your packages.el:
1 2 3 ;; ~/.doom.d/packages.el (package! org-reveal) (package! ox-reveal) Add some optional configuration to your config.el.
1 2 3 4 ;; ~/.doom.d/config.el (after! org (load-library &#34;ox-reveal&#34;) (setq org-reveal-root &#34;file:///path/to/reveal.]]></description></item><item><title>Arch Linux Unofficial user repositories</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/archlinuxuserrepository/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 16:56:00 +1100</pubDate><author>yanboyang713@gmail.com</author><dc:creator>Boyang Yan</dc:creator><guid>https://yanboyang.com/archlinuxuserrepository/</guid><description>Introduction archstrike In Arch Linux, the common way to install new software is install software from official repositorie. But, on some of special fields, there are lots of unofficial user repositorie is avaliable.
For example, archstrike is a famous repository for security professionals and enthusiasts.
In this article, I will tech you how to use others repositorie and how to make you own repositorie for share your package with others person.</description></item><item><title>Installing Wechat Desktop Client</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/wechat/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 15:44:00 +1100</pubDate><author>yanboyang713@gmail.com</author><dc:creator>Boyang Yan</dc:creator><guid>https://yanboyang.com/wechat/</guid><description>Introduction WeChat is a popular micro-messaging cross-platform app supporting text, image/videos, group chats with over 900 million active monthly users, mostly in China. Along with the basic messaging facilities, it also provides payment services in China to pay bills, order goods and services, transfer money and much more.
Currently there is no official Linux version of WeChat. This article will introduce how to install WeChat.
Using WeChat on Linux desktop Just as you saw for WhatsApp on Linux, WeChat can also be used via a web browser by scanning the QR code.</description></item></channel></rss>