<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Boyang Yan's Tech Blog</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/</link><description>This is Boyang Yan's Tech Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</managingEditor><webMaster>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 12:46:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yanboyang.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Getting Started with Zotero</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/zotero/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 12:46:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/zotero/</guid><description>Introduction Why Use Zotero? Be Organized: Keep all of your research and citations in one place Save time: Format fewer citations by hand Collaborate: Work with anyone in the world, anytime It&amp;rsquo;s Free: No cost even after you Zotero Installation 1 yay -S zotero Launch Zotero :zotero-sync: Create a Zotero Account If you haven’t already created a Zotero account, please take a few moments to register now Here .</description></item><item><title>Building a Second Brain: Capturing, Organizing, and Sharing Knowledge for Scholars and Researchers</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/secondbrain/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 10:18:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/secondbrain/</guid><description>Introduction Building a Second Brain is about creating a reliable system – outside your physical skin-and-bone bodily boundaries – for storing, organising, digesting, and eventually transforming information into Good Creative Output.
Much like any well-integrated tool, I am currently using Emacs Org Mode as Second Brain core tool. This system also includes many other peripheral components that make up the complete Second Brain system.
I will follow the below overview diagram introducte each components one by one.</description></item><item><title>Proxmox PCI Passthrough</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/proxmoxpassthrough/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 16:04:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/proxmoxpassthrough/</guid><description><![CDATA[Introduction PCI passthrough allows you to use a physical PCI device (graphics card, network card) inside a VM (KVM virtualization only).
If you &ldquo;PCI passthrough&rdquo; a device, the device is not available to the host anymore.
Note: PCI passthrough is an experimental feature in Proxmox VE! VMs with passthroughed devices cannot be migrated.
Enable the IOMMU First open your bootloader kernel command line config file.
1  vim /etc/default/grub   Find line GRUB_CMDLINE_LINUX_DEFAULT=&ldquo;quiet&rdquo;]]></description></item><item><title>Getting Started Fcitx with chinese input method in Linux</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/chineseinputmethod/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 13:56:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/chineseinputmethod/</guid><description>Introduction Fcitx is a lightweight input method framework aimed at providing environment independent language support for Linux. It supports a lot of different languages and also provides many useful non-CJK features.
In this article, I will introduction:
How to install Fcite in Manjaro/Arch Linux. How to Config Environmental variables Install fcite packages in Manjaro 1 yay -Syu adobe-source-han-sans-otc-fonts adobe-source-han-serif-otc-fonts 1 yay -Syu fcitx fcitx-googlepinyin fcitx-im fcitx-configtool Config Environmental variables 1 vim ~/.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started with send and receive Email with Doom Emacs</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/sendandreceiveemailwithdoom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 13:44:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/sendandreceiveemailwithdoom/</guid><description><![CDATA[Receive Email 1  yay -S mu mbsync-git   https://devanswers.co/create-application-specific-password-gmail/
1  gpg2 -c xxxxxxx   1 2 3 4  time mu init --maildir=~/MailDir --my-address=&#39;yanboyang713@gmail.com&#39; mu index time mbsync -c ~/.config/mu4e/mbsyncrc -a   [yanboyang713@Boyang-PC] ➜ ~ time mu init &ndash;maildir=~/MailDir &ndash;my-address='yanboyang713@gmail.com' error: failed to open store @ home/yanboyang713.cache/mu/xapian: Unable to get write lock on home/yanboyang713.cache/mu/xapian: already locked mu init &ndash;maildir=~/MailDir &ndash;my-address='yanboyang713@gmail.com' 0.00s user 0.00s system 66% cpu 0.]]></description></item><item><title>Getting Started Set-up OVS for Proxmox</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/proxmoxovs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 12:58:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/proxmoxovs/</guid><description>Introduction Install Open vSwitch Update the package index and then install the Open vSwitch packages by executing:
1 2 3 apt update apt install ifupdown2 apt install openvswitch-switch root@pve-home:~# cat etc/network/interfaces https://karneliuk.com/2021/08/infrastructure-1-building-virtualized-environment-with-debian-linux-and-proxmox-on-hp-and-supermicro
ifreload -a ifup vmbr0
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 auto lo iface lo inet loopback auto enp6s0 iface enp6s0 inet manual auto enp1s0 iface enp1s0 inet manual auto enp2s0 iface enp2s0 inet manual auto enp3s0 iface enp3s0 inet manual auto enp5s0 iface enp5s0 inet manual auto ens9 iface ens9 inet manual auto vlan1 iface vlan1 inet static address 192.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started MikroTik Cloud Hosted Router (CHR) on Proxmox</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/chronproxmox/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 12:28:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/chronproxmox/</guid><description>Introduction Cloud Hosted Router (CHR) is a RouterOS version intended for running as a virtual machine. It supports the x86 64-bit architecture and can be used on most of the popular hypervisors such as VMWare, Hyper-V, VirtualBox, KVM and others. CHR has full RouterOS features enabled by default but has a different licensing model than other RouterOS versions.
Prerequires read Cluster/Getting Started Set-up OVS for Proxmox read Cluster/Proxmox PCI Passthrough System Minimal Requirements Package version: RouterOS v6.</description></item><item><title>Create Proxmox cloud-init template</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/clouldinit/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 18:27:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/clouldinit/</guid><description>Overview In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll demonstrate how to create a cloud-init enabled Ubuntu 20.04 LTS base image to use on Proxmox VE.
Cloud Native Image The tradition packer builder to build a base image from an ISO file. Modern Linux distributions are increasingly moving away from this install method and preseed files. Rather, disk images are provided with the OS pre-installed, and configuration is performed via cloud-init. We will create a Proxmox KVM base image using Ubuntu&amp;rsquo;s KVM cloud image.</description></item><item><title>Ansible Beginner's Guide</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/ansible/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 17:58:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/ansible/</guid><description>Overview This article covers all the aspects of Ansible, a tool used in DevOps for the Management, Deployment, and Orchestration of IT Infrastructure.
What Is Ansible? Ansible is a simple configuration management and IT automation engine for multi-tier deployments. It automates both cloud and on-premise provisioning &amp;amp; configuration. It automates cloud provisioning. Rather than managing one system at a time, Ansible uses a model that inter-relates the entire IT infrastructure and enables you to manage everything using something called an Infrastructure as Code (IAC) approach.</description></item><item><title>DevOps Beginner's Guide</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/devops/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 11:18:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/devops/</guid><description><![CDATA[Overview In this blog, I discussed what is DevOps, and why it has gained so much traction in the IT industry lately.
What Is DevOps? It is a combination of practices that streamline the automation and integration of processes between the software development and IT teams. This will help them to build, test, and release software in a faster and more reliable way.
Purpose The term was formed by combining the words &ldquo;development&rdquo; and &ldquo;operations&rdquo; and signifies a cultural shift that helps bridge the gap between the development and operation teams.]]></description></item></channel></rss>