<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Linux - Category - Boyang Yan's Tech Blog</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/categories/linux/</link><description>Linux - Category - Boyang Yan's Tech Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</managingEditor><webMaster>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 18:59:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yanboyang.com/categories/linux/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Managing Your Dotfiles With Git and Make</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/dotfiles/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 18:59:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/dotfiles/</guid><description>Introduction User-specific application configuration is traditionally stored in so called dotfiles (files whose filename starts with a dot). It is common practice to track dotfiles with a version control system such as Git to keep track of changes and synchronize dotfiles across various hosts. There are various approaches to managing your dotfiles. In this article, I will talk about How to use Make with Git to management your dotfiles and package.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started Fcitx with chinese input method in Linux</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/chineseinputmethod/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 13:56:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/chineseinputmethod/</guid><description>Introduction Fcitx is a lightweight input method framework aimed at providing environment independent language support for Linux. It supports a lot of different languages and also provides many useful non-CJK features.
In this article, I will introduction:
How to install Fcite in Manjaro/Arch Linux. How to Config Environmental variables Install fcite packages in Manjaro 1 yay -Syu adobe-source-han-sans-otc-fonts adobe-source-han-serif-otc-fonts 1 yay -Syu fcitx fcitx-googlepinyin fcitx-im fcitx-configtool Config Environmental variables 1 vim ~/.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started Dynamic Window Manager (DWM)</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/dwm/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 17:50:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/dwm/</guid><description><![CDATA[Introduction Installing Install Xorg 1  pacman -S xorg-server xorg-xinit xorg-xrandr xorg-xsetroot   Install DWM 1 2 3  git clone git://git.suckless.org/dwm ~/.config/dwm git clone git://git.suckless.org/st ~/.config/st git clone git://git.suckless.org/dmenu ~/.config/dmenu   1 2 3  cd ~/.config/dwm &amp;&amp; sudo make install cd ~/.config/st &amp;&amp; sudo make install cd ~/.config/dmenu &amp;&amp; sudo make install   Installing a Display Manager (DM) 1 2 3 4 5  pacman -S lightdm pacman -S lightdm-gtk-greeter pacman -S lightdm-gtk-greeter-settings   Enable lightdm service 1  sudo systemctl enable lightdm   Adding an entry for DWM in the DM Create this file and add the following.]]></description></item><item><title>linux basic commands and common tools</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/linux/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 06:11:32 +1000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/linux/</guid><description>Hardware Information There are plenty of commands to check information about the hardware of Linux system. Some commands report only specific hardware components like CPU or memory while the rest cover multiple hardware units. This section will look at some of the most commonly used commands to check information and configuration details about various hardware peripherals and devices.
The list includes lscpu, hwinfo, lshw, dmidecode, lspci etc.
lscpu The lscpu command reports information about the cpu and processing units.</description></item><item><title>Manjaro Linux kernel headers installation</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/kernel/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 06:11:32 +1000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/kernel/</guid><description>Overview A Linux kernel is the core of a Linux distribution and consists of three things:
The kernel itself The kernel&amp;rsquo;s headers The kernel&amp;rsquo;s extra modules The kernel headers are used to define device interfaces. For example, they can be used to compile the module that controls your computer&amp;rsquo;s video card and driver.
The main reason you may find yourself needing to install kernel headers is if you are compiling kernel modules and need Linux to access and communicate with hardware as intended.</description></item><item><title>Manjaro Linux Tips</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/manjaro/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 06:11:32 +1000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/manjaro/</guid><description><![CDATA[I3 WM Screenshot Requirements  maim  1  yay -S xclip    xclip  1  yay -S maim   Set-up Set this on your i3 config file ~/.i3/config
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9  ## Screenshots bindsym Print exec --no-startup-id maim &#34;/home/$USER/Pictures/$(date)&#34; bindsym $mod+Print exec --no-startup-id maim --window $(xdotool getactivewindow) &#34;/home/$USER/Pictures/$(date)&#34; bindsym Shift+Print exec --no-startup-id maim --select &#34;/home/$USER/Pictures/$(date)&#34; ### Clipboard Screenshots bindsym Ctrl+Print exec --no-startup-id maim | xclip -selection clipboard -t image/png bindsym Ctrl+$mod+Print exec --no-startup-id maim --window $(xdotool getactivewindow) | xclip -selection clipboard -t image/png bindsym Ctrl+Shift+Print exec --no-startup-id maim --select | xclip -selection clipboard -t image/png   NOTE: You may remove the default screenshot shortcuts to prevent error.]]></description></item></channel></rss>