<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>spacemacs - Tag - Boyang Yan's Tech Blog</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/tags/spacemacs/</link><description>spacemacs - Tag - Boyang Yan's Tech Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</managingEditor><webMaster>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 06:11:32 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yanboyang.com/tags/spacemacs/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>An introduction to Magit, an Emacs mode for Git</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/magit/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 06:11:32 +1000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/magit/</guid><description>Introduction Magit is arguably the best Git tool out there and also my favorite. It is a package in Emacs, and it is text based.
Magit init, commit and commit messages Init create a repositories from a floder SPC g i(magit-init)
Add all of files to staged SPC u S
Checking staged files changed contect Move cursor to staged files, click TAB check what is changed
Commit c c then use c-c c-c to finish commit</description></item><item><title>Getting Started with Org Roam - Build a Second Brain in Emacs</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/roam/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 06:11:32 +1000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/roam/</guid><description>Introduction Org-roam is a plain-text knowledge management system. Org-roam is a tool for networked thought. It reproduces some of Roam Research’s 1 key features within Org-mode.
Org-roam borrows principles from the Zettelkasten method, providing a solution for non-hierarchical note-taking. It should also work as a plug-and-play solution for anyone already using Org-mode for their personal wiki.
Org-roam provides these benefits over other tooling:
Privacy and Security: Your personal wiki belongs only to you, entirely offline and in your control.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started with Spacemacs/Emacs</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/spacemacs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 06:11:32 +1000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/spacemacs/</guid><description>Day 11 Topic: Spacemacs introduction and installation
Why Spacemacs? You have your own Emacs configuration and you have used it for a long time. My suggest: Try Spacemacs, use it and learn from it. Then consider to use Spacemacs daily or stick to your own Emacs config. It’s a bundle of meta configs, it’s very easy to add/remove features &amp;amp; packages. The default package system is poor. It’s very friendly for Vim users.</description></item><item><title>Getting started with UML (Unified Modeling Language)</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/plantuml/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 06:11:32 +1000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/plantuml/</guid><description>Introduction This post document will brief introduct UML at the begining. After, will talk how using PlantUML for drawing UML diagrams. At the end, how does PlantUML integrate with Markdown and Emacs(Spacemacs).
UML Basics PlantUML Basics Reasons for using PlantUML Markdown Emacs (Spacemacs) Summary</description></item></channel></rss>