<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Blog - Category - Boyang Yan's Tech Blog</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/categories/blog/</link><description>Blog - Category - Boyang Yan's Tech Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 20:22:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yanboyang.com/categories/blog/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Verify Your Site For Bing Webmaster Tools - Bing SEO</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/bingseo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 20:22:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://yanboyang.com/bingseo/</guid><description>Introduction Bing Webmaster Tools optimizes your site and monitors its performance in Bing search engine results.
You should verify your site with Bing Webmaster Tools after launching your site.
Before you start, create a Microsoft account .
Steps
Log in to Bing with with your Microsoft Account. Under My Sites, enter your site&amp;rsquo;s URL. Click Add. On the Add a site page, in Add a sitemap, enter http://yoursite.com/sitemap%5Findex.xml .</description></item><item><title>Verify Your Site For Baidu Webmaster Tools - Baidu SEO</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/baiduseo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 13:13:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://yanboyang.com/baiduseo/</guid><description>Introduction Baidu Webmaster Tools, or Baidu Ziyuan, is a resource platform that tracks and enhances your site’s organic performance on Baidu, China’s #1 search engine with 222+ million active users.
In addition to enabling faster mobile indexation on Baidu and improved monitoring of your site’s crawlability, Baidu Ziyuan (Baidu Webmaster Tools) identifies and recommends critical SEO best practices and solutions unique to your site to improve your visibility on the most-used search engine in China: Baidu.</description></item><item><title>Creating a Hugo blog</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/hugo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 17:31:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://yanboyang.com/hugo/</guid><description>Overview This is a tutorial on creating a blog or website using hugo (a static site generator).
We will use Docker as our development environment. Also, we will storge our Hugo development code in Github main branche and automate the whole process with Github Action Workflow for Github Pages.
Prerequisites You will need to have the following:
Docker installation. Docker is available for Mac/Windows/Linux and is easily installed. You can following the link at the below for install Docker.</description></item><item><title>Exporting Org Roam notes to hugo</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/roamtohugo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 13:20:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://yanboyang.com/roamtohugo/</guid><description>Introduction Pre-reading Read this article: Blog/Creating a Hugo blog and Set-up your HUGO blog References https://sidhartharya.me/exporting-org-roam-notes-to-hugo/</description></item><item><title>Creating a Hexo blog with Docker</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/hexowithdocker/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 06:11:32 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://yanboyang.com/hexowithdocker/</guid><description>Overview This is a tutorial on creating a blog or website using hexo.io (a static site generator).
We will use Docker as our development environment. Also, we will storge our Hexo development code in Github main branche and all of our generate static pages will hosting in Github Page on gh-pages branches with your own custom domain and https.
Why we choose Hexo After comparing a multitude of offerings, I settled on the excellent hexo.</description></item></channel></rss>