<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>ComputerVision - Category - Boyang Yan's Tech Blog</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/categories/computervision/</link><description>ComputerVision - Category - Boyang Yan's Tech Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</managingEditor><webMaster>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 11:43:00 +1100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yanboyang.com/categories/computervision/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Gettting Started SRS(Simple Realtime Server)</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/srs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 11:43:00 +1100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/srs/</guid><description>Overview SRS is a simple, high efficiency and realtime video server, supports RTMP/WebRTC/HLS/HTTP-FLV/SRT.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started ROS and Openwrt with Proxmox</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/rosandopenwrtproxmox/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 19:52:00 +1100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/rosandopenwrtproxmox/</guid><description>Install Open vSwitch Update the package index and then install the Open vSwitch packages by executing:
1 2 3 apt update apt install ifupdown2 apt install openvswitch-switch root@pve-home:~# cat etc/network/interfaces https://karneliuk.com/2021/08/infrastructure-1-building-virtualized-environment-with-debian-linux-and-proxmox-on-hp-and-supermicro
ifreload -a ifup vmbr0
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 auto lo iface lo inet loopback auto enp6s0 iface enp6s0 inet manual auto enp1s0 iface enp1s0 inet manual auto enp2s0 iface enp2s0 inet manual auto enp3s0 iface enp3s0 inet manual auto enp5s0 iface enp5s0 inet manual auto ens9 iface ens9 inet manual auto vlan1 iface vlan1 inet static address 192.</description></item><item><title>Beginning Explore artificial intelligence and computer vision</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/firstexploreaiandcomputervision/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 19:17:00 +1100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/firstexploreaiandcomputervision/</guid><description>What is artificial intelligence? Explore into artificial intelligence For the definition of artificial intelligence, academic research area always have different understandings. The widely accepted definition is:
Artificial intelligence is the use of machines to simulate human cognitive abilities technology. Artificial intelligence involves a wide range of insights, learning, reasoning and decision-making.
From the perspective of industry application, the core ability of artificial intelligence ability is to make judgments or predictions based on given input.</description></item></channel></rss>