<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nix - Category - Boyang Yan's Tech Blog</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/categories/nix/</link><description>Nix - Category - Boyang Yan's Tech Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</managingEditor><webMaster>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 11:23:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yanboyang.com/categories/nix/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Nix Flakes</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/nixflakes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 11:23:00 +0800</pubDate><author>yanboyang713@gmail.com</author><dc:creator>Boyang Yan</dc:creator><guid>https://yanboyang.com/nixflakes/</guid><description>Introduction Nix Flakes are an upcoming feature of the Nix package manager.
Flakes replace stateful channels (which cause much confusion among novices) and introduce a more intuitive and consistent CLI, making them a perfect opportunity to start using Nix.
It contains examples and advice on using flakes for a real-life use case: building applications in various languages.
Pre-reading Nix/Getting Started with Nix Installing flakes In order to do anything with flakes, you will first have to get “unstable” Nix up and running on your machine.</description></item><item><title>Home Manager using Nix</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/nixhomemanager/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 17:30:00 +0800</pubDate><author>yanboyang713@gmail.com</author><dc:creator>Boyang Yan</dc:creator><guid>https://yanboyang.com/nixhomemanager/</guid><description>Standalone installation Add the appropriate Home Manager channel. If you are following Nixpkgs master or an unstable channel you can run.
1 2 nix-channel --add https://github.com/nix-community/home-manager/archive/master.tar.gz home-manager nix-channel --update 1 2 cat ~/.nix-channels nix-channel --list Check your echo $NIX_PATH, If your have NOT
you may have to add
1 2 3 4 5 6 export NIX_PATH=$HOME/.nix-defexpr/channels${NIX_PATH:+:}$NIX_PATH /nix/var/nix/profiles/per-user/yanboyang713/channels export NIX_PATH=nixpkgs=/nix/var/nix/profiles/per-user/yanboyang713/channels/nixpkgs:/nix/var/nix/profiles/per-user/yanboyang713/channels:~/.nix-defexpr/channels to your shell
Run the Home Manager installation command and create the first Home Manager generation:</description></item><item><title>Nix Installation</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/nixinstallation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 15:18:00 +0800</pubDate><author>yanboyang713@gmail.com</author><dc:creator>Boyang Yan</dc:creator><guid>https://yanboyang.com/nixinstallation/</guid><description>Supported Platforms Nix is currently supported on the following platforms:
Linux (i686, x86_64, aarch64). macOS (x86_64). Installing a Binary Distribution We recommend the multi-user install if it supports your platform and you can authenticate with sudo.
Single User Installation To explicitly select a single-user installation on your system:
1 sh &amp;lt;(curl -L https://nixos.org/nix/install) --no-daemon This will perform a single-user installation of Nix, meaning that /nix is owned by the invoking user.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started with Nix</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/nix/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2021 12:34:00 +0800</pubDate><author>yanboyang713@gmail.com</author><dc:creator>Boyang Yan</dc:creator><guid>https://yanboyang.com/nix/</guid><description>Introduction The NixOS package manager is a system of its own. You can use it under any Linux Distribution.
What is Nix? Briefly speaking, Nix is a package manager and a build system. Its most important aspect is allowing to write declarative scripts for reproducible software builds. It also helps to test and deploy software systems while using the functional programming paradigm. There is a vast repository of packages for Nix called nixpkgs , and a GNU/Linux distribution that extends the ideas of Nix to the OS level called NixOS .</description></item></channel></rss>