<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0"><channel><title>proxmox - Tag - Boyang Yan's Tech Blog</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/tags/proxmox/</link><description>proxmox - Tag - Boyang Yan's Tech Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</managingEditor><webMaster>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 18:17:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yanboyang.com/tags/proxmox/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Beginner guide to install Proxmox</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/proxmoxinstall/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 18:17:00 +0800</pubDate><author>yanboyang713@gmail.com</author><dc:creator>Boyang Yan</dc:creator><guid>https://yanboyang.com/proxmoxinstall/</guid><description>Introduction Proxmox Virtual Environment is an open source server virtualization management solution based on QEMU/KVM and LXC. Proxmox VE is based on Debian. You can manage virtual machines, containers, highly available clusters, storage and networks with an integrated, easy-to-use web interface or via CLI.
Install I recommend you use USB Flash Drive as Installation Medium because it is the faster option.
Download the installer ISO image You can download ISO image from: https://www.</description></item><item><title>Using Ceph with Proxmox</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/cephonproxmox/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 12:23:00 +0800</pubDate><author>yanboyang713@gmail.com</author><dc:creator>Boyang Yan</dc:creator><guid>https://yanboyang.com/cephonproxmox/</guid><description>Objective This guide explains how to set up the Cloud Disk Array on Proxmox.
Requirements Fist of all, you need your Cloud Disk Array up and ready. Make sure you have:
created a cluster pool for storing data created a Ceph user that Proxmox will use to access the CDA cluster configured permissions for this user and pool (allow read and write) configured your IP access control list to allow Proxmox nodes to access the CDA</description></item><item><title>Virtualize Windows 11 with Proxmox</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/windows11pve/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 12:37:00 +1100</pubDate><author>yanboyang713@gmail.com</author><dc:creator>Boyang Yan</dc:creator><guid>https://yanboyang.com/windows11pve/</guid><description><![CDATA[Introduction As Microsoft released Windows 11, it was made clear that TPM 2.0 and Secure boot is no longer optional but mandatory, without these capabilities on the hardware/virtual hardware, Windows 11 refuse to install.
Step 1: Download Windows 11 ISO You can click Here  for download ISO file.
Step 2: Download virtio-win drivers disk You can click Here  , download Latest virtio-win ISO.
Step 3: Upload Windows 11 ISO and Latest virtio-win ISO to ProxMox login to ProxMox -&gt; choose Node -&gt; local (pve) -&gt; ISO Images -&gt; Upload]]></description></item><item><title>Proxmox PCI Passthrough</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/proxmoxpassthrough/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 16:04:00 +0800</pubDate><author>yanboyang713@gmail.com</author><dc:creator>Boyang Yan</dc:creator><guid>https://yanboyang.com/proxmoxpassthrough/</guid><description><![CDATA[Introduction PCI passthrough allows you to use a physical PCI device (graphics card, network card) inside a VM (KVM virtualization only).
If you &ldquo;PCI passthrough&rdquo; a device, the device is not available to the host anymore.
Note: PCI passthrough is an experimental feature in Proxmox VE! VMs with passthroughed devices cannot be migrated.
Enable the IOMMU First open your bootloader kernel command line config file.
1  vim /etc/default/grub   Find line GRUB_CMDLINE_LINUX_DEFAULT=&ldquo;quiet&rdquo;]]></description></item><item><title>Getting Started MikroTik Cloud Hosted Router (CHR) on Proxmox</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/chronproxmox/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 12:28:00 +0800</pubDate><author>yanboyang713@gmail.com</author><dc:creator>Boyang Yan</dc:creator><guid>https://yanboyang.com/chronproxmox/</guid><description>Introduction Cloud Hosted Router (CHR) is a RouterOS version intended for running as a virtual machine. It supports the x86 64-bit architecture and can be used on most of the popular hypervisors such as VMWare, Hyper-V, VirtualBox, KVM and others. CHR has full RouterOS features enabled by default but has a different licensing model than other RouterOS versions.
Prerequires read Cluster/Getting Started Set-up OVS for Proxmox read Cluster/Proxmox PCI Passthrough System Minimal Requirements Package version: RouterOS v6.</description></item><item><title>Create Proxmox cloud-init template</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/clouldinit/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 18:27:00 +0800</pubDate><author>yanboyang713@gmail.com</author><dc:creator>Boyang Yan</dc:creator><guid>https://yanboyang.com/clouldinit/</guid><description>Overview In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll demonstrate how to create a cloud-init enabled Ubuntu 20.04 LTS base image to use on Proxmox VE.
Cloud Native Image The tradition packer builder to build a base image from an ISO file. Modern Linux distributions are increasingly moving away from this install method and preseed files. Rather, disk images are provided with the OS pre-installed, and configuration is performed via cloud-init. We will create a Proxmox KVM base image using Ubuntu&amp;rsquo;s KVM cloud image.</description></item><item><title>Build a Kubernetes cluster on Proxmox via Ansible and Terraform</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/k8sonproxmox/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 20:27:00 +0800</pubDate><author>yanboyang713@gmail.com</author><dc:creator>Boyang Yan</dc:creator><guid>https://yanboyang.com/k8sonproxmox/</guid><description>Overview Proxmox is an open-source hypervisor that have enterprise capabilities and a large community behind it.
For Terraform and Ansible, I always like the idea of infrastructure as code (iac) and Terraform and Ansible just make it easy to accomplish.
The idea here was to be able to spin up a k3s cluster with minimum effort so I can spin it up and down for ever project that I would like to run.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started Configuring VLANs on Proxmox</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/vlan/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 19:52:00 +0800</pubDate><author>yanboyang713@gmail.com</author><dc:creator>Boyang Yan</dc:creator><guid>https://yanboyang.com/vlan/</guid><description>Introduction A virtualization server allows you to run multiple machines, virtual machines (VMs), on one physical device, also known as the host. There could be many different VMs each for different tasks. In this guide, we will discuss configuring your Proxmox virtualization server to use VLANs so that you can group related VMs onto their own subnet.
Motivation For security, as well as organizational purposes, physical machines are often separated on the network from each other by VLANs.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started ROS and Openwrt with Proxmox</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/rosandopenwrtproxmox/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 19:52:00 +0800</pubDate><author>yanboyang713@gmail.com</author><dc:creator>Boyang Yan</dc:creator><guid>https://yanboyang.com/rosandopenwrtproxmox/</guid><description>mikrotik https://mikrotik.com/software OpenWrt https://openwrt.org/downloads https://downloads.openwrt.org/releases/21.02.1/targets/x86/ https://downloads.openwrt.org/releases/21.02.1/targets/x86/64/ Migration of servers to Proxmox VE https://pve.proxmox.com/wiki/Migration%5Fof%5Fservers%5Fto%5FProxmox%5FVE VLAN https://engineerworkshop.com/blog/configuring-vlans-on-proxmox-an-introductory-guide/</description></item><item><title>Get started with LXC Container in Proxmox</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/lxccontainerproxmox/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 06:11:32 +1000</pubDate><author>yanboyang713@gmail.com</author><dc:creator>Boyang Yan</dc:creator><guid>https://yanboyang.com/lxccontainerproxmox/</guid><description>Introduction https://pve.proxmox.com/wiki/Linux_Container Containers are a lightweight alternative to fully virtualized machines (VMs). They use the kernel of the host system that they run on, instead of emulating a full operating system (OS). This means that containers can access resources on the host system directly.
The runtime costs for containers is low, usually negligible. However, there are some drawbacks that need be considered:
Only Linux distributions can be run in Proxmox Containers.</description></item></channel></rss>