<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>r on Boyang Yan&#39;s Tech Blog</title>
    <link>https://yanboyang.com/tags/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in r on Boyang Yan&#39;s Tech Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 06:11:32 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yanboyang.com/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with R language</title>
      <link>https://yanboyang.com/rlanguage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 06:11:32 +1000</pubDate>
      <author>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</author>
      <guid>https://yanboyang.com/rlanguage/</guid>
      <description>Summary This course will get you started with learning R and using the RStudio IDE. The course will cover installation of R and RStudio and using RStudio’s basic features and the basics of R programming.
Learning Objectives By the end of this course, you will have covered the following:
 Installing R and RStudio An overview of the RStudio interface Basic programming in R  Why we learn R In this blog, you won’t learn anything about Excel, SPSS, SQL, SAS, Python, Julia, or any other statistical package/programming language useful for data preprocessing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launching RStudio in Docker</title>
      <link>https://yanboyang.com/rstudio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 06:11:32 +1000</pubDate>
      <author>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</author>
      <guid>https://yanboyang.com/rstudio/</guid>
      <description>Introduction RStudio Server enables you to provide a browser based interface to a version of R running on a remote Linux server, bringing the power and productivity of the RStudio IDE to server-based deployments of R.
In this blog, I will talk about how to launch a Docker container that allows us to run RStudio in a browser using the &amp;ndash;rm flag when we run Docker makes the container ephemeral that mean it is automatically deleted after we close the container.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
