<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0"><channel><title>time - Tag - Boyang Yan's Tech Blog</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/tags/time/</link><description>time - Tag - Boyang Yan's Tech Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</managingEditor><webMaster>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 00:04:00 +1100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yanboyang.com/tags/time/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Analysis of Trends</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/analysisoftrends/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 00:04:00 +1100</pubDate><author>yanboyang713@gmail.com</author><dc:creator>Boyang Yan</dc:creator><guid>https://yanboyang.com/analysisoftrends/</guid><description>Introduction We will study trend models for the analysis of time series data. Trend models that we will cover include linear, quadratic and harmonic trend models and those account for seasonality. We will observe that while the trend models are very good at capturing the trend in time series data, their performance is poor on capturing serial correlation in time series data. We will have hands-on tasks to deepen your understanding of trend models and improve your skillsets for the implementation of time series analysis methods.</description></item><item><title>Time Series Analysis Basic Plots, Examples, and Fundamental Concepts</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/timeseriesanalysisweek1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 18:23:00 +1100</pubDate><author>yanboyang713@gmail.com</author><dc:creator>Boyang Yan</dc:creator><guid>https://yanboyang.com/timeseriesanalysisweek1/</guid><description>Introduction You will study the basic context of time series and stochastic processes including basic visualisations for time series data.
Time series data is composed of observations collected sequentially over time. This type of data is frequently seen and analysed in data analytics applications.
In business, we observe
weekly interest rates, daily closing stock prices, monthly price indices, yearly sales figures, and so forth. In meteorology, we observe</description></item></channel></rss>