<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SDN on Boyang Yan&#39;s Tech Blog</title>
    <link>https://yanboyang.com/tags/sdn/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SDN on Boyang Yan&#39;s Tech Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</webMaster><atom:link href="https://yanboyang.com/tags/sdn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started Mininet</title>
      <link>https://yanboyang.com/mininet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</author>
      <guid>https://yanboyang.com/mininet/</guid>
      <description>Mininet Overview Mininet is a network emulator which creates a network of virtual hosts, switches, controllers, and links. Mininet hosts run standard Linux network software, and its switches support OpenFlow for highly flexible custom routing and Software-Defined Networking.
Mininet supports research, development, learning, prototyping, testing, debugging, and any other tasks that could benefit from having a complete experimental network on a laptop or other PC.
Mininet:
 Provides a simple and inexpensive network testbed for developing OpenFlow applications Enables multiple concurrent developers to work independently on the same topology Supports system-level regression tests, which are repeatable and easily packaged Enables complex topology testing, without the need to wire up a physical network Includes a CLI that is topology-aware and OpenFlow-aware, for debugging or running network-wide tests Supports arbitrary custom topologies, and includes a basic set of parametrized topologies is usable out of the box without programming, but also Provides a straightforward and extensible Python API for network creation and experimentation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
