<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Azure on Boyang Yan&#39;s Tech Blog</title>
    <link>https://yanboyang.com/categories/azure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Azure on Boyang Yan&#39;s Tech Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 06:11:32 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yanboyang.com/categories/azure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Azure Networking</title>
      <link>https://yanboyang.com/azurevnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 06:11:32 +1000</pubDate>
      <author>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</author>
      <guid>https://yanboyang.com/azurevnet/</guid>
      <description>Create a virtual network using the Azure CLI A virtual network enables Azure resources, like virtual machines (VMs), to communicate privately with each other, and with the internet. In this quickstart, you learn how to create a virtual network. After creating a virtual network, you deploy two VMs into the virtual network. You then connect to the VMs from the internet, and communicate privately over the new virtual network.
Create a resource group and a virtual network Before you can create a virtual network, you have to create a resource group to host the virtual network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://yanboyang.com/aml/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 06:11:32 +1000</pubDate>
      <author>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</author>
      <guid>https://yanboyang.com/aml/</guid>
      <description>Create a new Azure Machine Learning I recommand you create a new AML workspace use an Azure Resource Manager Template from Azure CLI. The Azure Resource Manager template can be found in the 201-machine-learning-advanced in GitHub repository.
This template creates the following Azure services, all those various services are required by the Azure Machine Learning workspace:
 Azure Storage Account Azure Key Vault Azure Application Insights Azure Container Registry Azure Machine Learning workspace  Firstly, we need create a resource group, there is a example at the below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Data Science Virtual Machine Getting Started</title>
      <link>https://yanboyang.com/dsvm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 06:11:32 +1000</pubDate>
      <author>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</author>
      <guid>https://yanboyang.com/dsvm/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Azure Data Science Virtual Machine(DSVM) is Azure Virtual Machine image, pre-installed, configured and tested with several popular tools that are data analytics, machine learning and AI training. DSVM will be your best option as your develop environment base on cloud. DSVM helps in flexible virtualization without the need for purchasing and maintenance of hardware. You will see the DSVM highlights at the below section. DSVM almost cover all of popular tools for data science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Machine Learning Compute Instance Getting Started</title>
      <link>https://yanboyang.com/amlci/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 06:11:32 +1000</pubDate>
      <author>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</author>
      <guid>https://yanboyang.com/amlci/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This post document is a brief introduction about Azure Machine Learning Service Compute Instance(CI). CI can be as your development environment or training compute tartget. TIPS: However, if your specialty on Linux, I recommand you using DSVM ({% post_link DSVM %}) as your development environment. For training process, I recommand you using Azure Machine Learning training cluster(Compute cluster).
Managing a compute instance From portal In your workspace in Azure Machine Learning studio, select Compute, then select Compute Instance on the top.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Machine Learning Workspace Authentication Troubleshooting Guide</title>
      <link>https://yanboyang.com/amlworkspaceauthentication/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 06:11:32 +1000</pubDate>
      <author>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</author>
      <guid>https://yanboyang.com/amlworkspaceauthentication/</guid>
      <description>Could you try using config.json file connect to your Azure ML Workspace first? The steps you can following at the below.
 Go to https://portal.azure.com/ Download config.json config.json Story config.json to the same directory as your Python code. run python code at the below  1 2 3  from azureml.core import Workspace ws = Workspace.from_config() print(&amp;#34;Found workspace {}at location {}&amp;#34;.format(ws.name, ws.location))    If using config.json file connect to your Azure ML Workspace does not work, please check your SDK version and update your SDK.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Azure CLI</title>
      <link>https://yanboyang.com/azurecli/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 06:11:32 +1000</pubDate>
      <author>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</author>
      <guid>https://yanboyang.com/azurecli/</guid>
      <description>Run Azure CLI in a Docker container You can use Docker to run a standalone Linux container with the Azure CLI pre-installed. Docker gets you started quickly with an isolated environment to run the CLI in. The image can also be used as a base for your own deployments.
Run in a Docker container Install Install the CLI using docker run.
1  docker run -it mcr.microsoft.com/azure-cli   NOTE:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with Azure Container Registry (ACR)</title>
      <link>https://yanboyang.com/acr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 06:11:32 +1000</pubDate>
      <author>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</author>
      <guid>https://yanboyang.com/acr/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Azure Container Registry is a managed, private Docker registry service based on the open-source Docker Registry 2.0. Create and maintain Azure container registries to store and manage your private Docker container images and related artifacts.
Use Azure container registries with your existing container development and deployment pipelines, or use Azure Container Registry Tasks to build container images in Azure. Build on demand, or fully automate builds with triggers such as source code commits and base image updates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Azure Container Instances with Azure Machine Learning Service</title>
      <link>https://yanboyang.com/aci/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 06:11:32 +1000</pubDate>
      <author>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</author>
      <guid>https://yanboyang.com/aci/</guid>
      <description>Stop and Start ACI for AML endpoint You can use Azure command-line interface (Azure CLI) to stop and start the Azure Container Instances.
The steps at the below.
Step 1: Go to your portal and click Cloud Shell Step 2: Check the Container Name using the below command. &amp;ldquo;sklearn-mnist-svc-4dea&amp;rdquo; is my Endpoint name az container list | grep &amp;ldquo;sklearn-mnist-svc-4dea&amp;rdquo; Step 3: Confirm your Container Name for your Endpoint using the below command.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Raise Support Ticket/Case and Troubleshooting Guide</title>
      <link>https://yanboyang.com/azureraisecase/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</author>
      <guid>https://yanboyang.com/azureraisecase/</guid>
      <description>Introduction When you use the Azure platform, you can open a case/ticket at any time when you encounter problems or have questions.
The steps for raise a new case/ticket  Go to portal. Click question mark.  Click &amp;ldquo;Help+support&amp;rdquo;  Click + New support request  You can open a Technical support request. There is an example.   Troubleshooting Permission Issue If you face the error MSG at the below.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
