<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Research - Category - Boyang Yan's Tech Blog</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/categories/research/</link><description>Research - Category - Boyang Yan's Tech Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</managingEditor><webMaster>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 15:08:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yanboyang.com/categories/research/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Getting Started with Org Roam</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/orgroam/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 15:08:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/orgroam/</guid><description>Set-up org roam</description></item><item><title>Getting Started with Zotero</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/zotero/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 12:46:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/zotero/</guid><description>Set-up Zotero with Better Bibtex, zotfile and Scite.</description></item><item><title>Building a Second Brain</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/secondbrain/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 10:18:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/secondbrain/</guid><description>Introduction Building a Second Brain is about creating a reliable system – outside your physical skin-and-bone bodily boundaries – for storing, organising, digesting, and eventually transforming information into Good Creative Output.
Much like any well-integrated tool, I am currently using Emacs Org Mode as Second Brain core tool. This system also includes many other peripheral components that make up the complete Second Brain system.
I will follow the below overview diagram introducte each components one by one.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started reproducible research with GNU Emacs</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/research/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 06:11:32 +1000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/research/</guid><description>Introduction Prerequirements Notes The idea is to be able to create notes for all kinds of content. Specifically, papers or books, along with webpages. This then requires a separate system for each which is described by:
Search Engine The search engine is key, both in terms of accessibility and scalability. It is assumed that there will be many notes, and that they will have a wide variety of content. The search interface must then simply allow us to narrow down our candidates in a meaningful manner.</description></item></channel></rss>