<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>All Posts - Boyang Yan's Tech Blog</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/posts/</link><description>All Posts | Boyang Yan's Tech Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 06:11:32 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yanboyang.com/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ESXi</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/esxi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 06:11:32 +1000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/esxi/</guid><description>ESXi Installation Prerequisites Linux machine with superuser access to it USB flash drive that can be detected by the Linux machine The ESXi ISO image, VMware-VMvisor-Installer-version_number-build_number.x86_64.iso, which includes the isolinux.cfg file Syslinux package Procedure Determine USB flash drive (1). list disk using fdisk 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 [yanboyang713@boyang ~]$ sudo fdisk -l [sudo] password for yanboyang713: Disk /dev/nvme0n1: 465.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started with Flink</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/flink/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 06:11:32 +1000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/flink/</guid><description>https://flink.apache.org/downloads.html</description></item><item><title>Getting Started with Spacemacs</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/spacemacs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 06:11:32 +1000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/spacemacs/</guid><description><![CDATA[installation 1  yay -S emacs   1  yay -S adobe-source-code-pro-fonts   clone spacemacs repo and use develop branch
1  git clone https://github.com/syl20bnr/spacemacs.git ~/.emacs.d -b develop   clone zilongshanren layer and checkout develop branch
1  git clone https://github.com/yanboyang713/spacemacs-private.git ~/.spacemacs.d/   1 2 3 4  [yanboyang713@boyang ~]$ gpg --homedir ~/.emacs.d/elpa/gnupg --receive-keys 066DAFCB81E42C40 gpg: key 066DAFCB81E42C40: &#34;GNU ELPA Signing Agent (2019) &lt;elpasign@elpa.gnu.org&gt;&#34; not changed gpg: Total number processed: 1 gpg: unchanged: 1   ]]></description></item><item><title>Writing Mathematic Fomular</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/writingmathematicfomular/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 06:11:32 +1000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/writingmathematicfomular/</guid><description>Greek Letters Symbol Script $$\begin{equation}\alpha\end{equation}$$ \alpha $A$ A $\beta$ \beta $B$ B $\gamma$ \gammma $\Gamma$ \Gamma $\pi$ \pi $\Pi$ \Pi $\phi$ \phi $\Phi$ \Phi $\varphi$ \varphi $\theta$ \theta Operators Symbol Script $\cos$ \cos $\sin$ \sin $\lim$ \lim $\exp$ \exp $\to$ \to $\infty$ \infty $\equiv$ \equiv $\bmod$ \bmod $\times$ \times Power and Indices Symbol Script $k_{n+1}$ k_{n+1} $n^2$ n^2 $k_n^2$ k_n^2 Fractions and Binomials Symbol Script $\frac{n!</description></item><item><title>Data Wrangling (Data Preprocessing)</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/datapreprocessing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 06:11:32 +1000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/datapreprocessing/</guid><description>Module 1 - Data Preprocessing: From Raw Data to Ready to Analyse Summary Module 1 will set the background for the entire course. Data preprocessing will be defined and the importance of data preprocessing inside the data analysis workflow will be explored. The module will define 5 major tasks for data preprocessing and will provide a quick overview of these tasks. Then, in the following modules of this course, we will unwrap each data preprocessing task by providing details of operations related to that task.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started with R language</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/rlanguage/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 06:11:32 +1000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/rlanguage/</guid><description>Summary This course will get you started with learning R and using the RStudio IDE. The course will cover installation of R and RStudio and using RStudio’s basic features and the basics of R programming.
Learning Objectives By the end of this course, you will have covered the following:
Installing R and RStudio An overview of the RStudio interface Basic programming in R Why we learn R In this blog, you won’t learn anything about Excel, SPSS, SQL, SAS, Python, Julia, or any other statistical package/programming language useful for data preprocessing.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Statistics (Applied Analytics)</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/introductiontostatistics-appliedanalytics/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 06:11:32 +1000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/introductiontostatistics-appliedanalytics/</guid><description>What is Statistics? Statistics is the science of collecting, organizing, analyzing, and interpreting data in order to make decisions.
Some informal definitions of statistics, provided by various well-known statisticians, are
The science of learning from (or making sense out of) data (J. Kettenring). The theory and methods of extracting information from observational data for solving real-world problems (C.R. Rao). The science of uncertainty (D.J. Hand). The art of telling a story with data (L.</description></item><item><title>4 big data architectures, Data Streaming, Lambda architecture, Kappa architecture and Unifield architecture</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/bigdataarchitectures/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 06:11:32 +1000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/bigdataarchitectures/</guid><description>Introduction Although data analysis is hidden behind the business system, it has a very important role. The results of data analysis play a pivotal role in decision-making and business development. With the development of big data technology, the exposure of proper terms such as data mining and data exploration is getting higher and higher, but before big data analysis systems similar to the Hadoop become popular, data analysis work has undergone considerable development, especially data analysis based on BI systems already has very mature and stable technical solutions and ecosystems.</description></item><item><title>Getting started SQLite</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/sqlite/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 06:11:32 +1000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/sqlite/</guid><description>Introduction In this tutorial, you will learn SQLite step by step through extensive hands-on practices. This SQLite tutorial is designed for developers who want to use SQLite as the back-end database or to use SQLite to manage structured data in applications including desktop, web, and mobile apps. SQLite is an open-source, zero-configuration, self-contained, stand-alone, transaction relational database engine designed to be embedded into an application.
Getting started with SQLite You should go through this section if this is the first time you have worked with SQLite.</description></item><item><title>Launching RStudio in Docker</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/rstudio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 06:11:32 +1000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/rstudio/</guid><description>Introduction RStudio Server enables you to provide a browser based interface to a version of R running on a remote Linux server, bringing the power and productivity of the RStudio IDE to server-based deployments of R.
In this blog, I will talk about how to launch a Docker container that allows us to run RStudio in a browser using the &amp;ndash;rm flag when we run Docker makes the container ephemeral that mean it is automatically deleted after we close the container.</description></item></channel></rss>