<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>All Posts - Boyang Yan's Tech Blog</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/posts/</link><description>All Posts | Boyang Yan's Tech Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</managingEditor><webMaster>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 19:04:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yanboyang.com/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Arch Linux/Manjaro sound and sound card configuration</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/configsound/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 19:04:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/configsound/</guid><description>Introduction After install Arch Linux/Manjaro, although alsa-utils has been installed, it may still not play sound correctly. Here is a solution.
First try 1 amixer sset Master unmute If you use alsamixer to unmute the master sound, you still can&amp;rsquo;t play the sound.
Please, following the steps at the below.
NOTE: If you faced maixer: Unable to find simple cintrol &amp;lsquo;Master&amp;rsquo;, 0, that means, it maybe that the sound card device cannot be found or the sound card driver us not installed.</description></item><item><title>Virtualize Windows 11 with Proxmox</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/windows11pve/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 12:37:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/windows11pve/</guid><description><![CDATA[Introduction As Microsoft released Windows 11, it was made clear that TPM 2.0 and Secure boot is no longer optional but mandatory, without these capabilities on the hardware/virtual hardware, Windows 11 refuse to install.
Step 1: Download Windows 11 ISO You can click Here for download ISO file.
Step 2: Download virtio-win drivers disk You can click Here, download Latest virtio-win ISO.
Step 3: Upload Windows 11 ISO and Latest virtio-win ISO to ProxMox login to ProxMox -&gt; choose Node -&gt; local (pve) -&gt; ISO Images -&gt; Upload]]></description></item><item><title>Managing Your Dotfiles With Git and Make</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/dotfiles/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 18:59:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/dotfiles/</guid><description>Introduction User-specific application configuration is traditionally stored in so called dotfiles (files whose filename starts with a dot). It is common practice to track dotfiles with a version control system such as Git to keep track of changes and synchronize dotfiles across various hosts. There are various approaches to managing your dotfiles. In this article, I will talk about How to use Make with Git to management your dotfiles and package.</description></item><item><title>Install Terrafom with Quick start tutorial</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/terraforminstall/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 17:39:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/terraforminstall/</guid><description><![CDATA[Pre-reading  DevOps/DevOps Beginner&rsquo;s Guide DevOps/Terraform Beginner&rsquo;s Guide DevOps/The comparison and introduction between Terraform and Ansible  Install Arch Linux 1  yay -S terraform   Ubuntu/Debian Ensure that your system is up to date, and you have the gnupg, software-properties-common, and curl packages installed. You will use these packages to verify HashiCorp&rsquo;s GPG signature, and install HashiCorp&rsquo;s Debian package repository.
1  sudo apt-get update &amp;&amp; sudo apt-get install -y gnupg software-properties-common curl   Add the HashiCorp GPG key.]]></description></item><item><title>Using Emacs Org-Babel Mode to Write Literate Programming Documents</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/orgbabel/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 10:29:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/orgbabel/</guid><description>Introduction We introduce the use of emacs org-babel model in this document. Emacs Org-Babel mode is a literate programming tool (aka. active document), which can embed multiple programming languages, inlcuding R, Python, C/C++ in one document. Babel has ability to execute source code within Org-mode documents.
Pre-reading Emacs/Getting Started Org-mode on Emacs Source Code Insert &amp;amp; Running Here is an format example:
1 2 #+BEGIN_SRC language #+END_SRC Reference List https://orgmode.</description></item><item><title>Best practices for using Emacs org-mode as a day-planner/scheduler/calendar</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/orgplanning/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 18:28:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/orgplanning/</guid><description>Pre-reading Emacs/Getting Started Org-mode on Emacs Checkbox It often great to split a task into a number of simple steps. Or you can use them in a shopping list.
The form is [], put in front of the task can mark the completion status of the task, Put it after the task to mark the completion degree of the task, which needs to add % or /
Here is an example of a checkbox list.</description></item><item><title>Verify Your Site For Bing Webmaster Tools - Bing SEO</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/bingseo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 20:22:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/bingseo/</guid><description>Introduction Bing Webmaster Tools optimizes your site and monitors its performance in Bing search engine results.
You should verify your site with Bing Webmaster Tools after launching your site.
Before you start, create a Microsoft account.
Steps
Log in to Bing with with your Microsoft Account. Under My Sites, enter your site&amp;rsquo;s URL. Click Add. On the Add a site page, in Add a sitemap, enter http://yoursite.com/sitemap%5Findex.xml. Optionally select the time of day when you anticipate the most traffic to your site, then click Add.</description></item><item><title>Verify Your Site For Baidu Webmaster Tools - Baidu SEO</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/baiduseo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 13:13:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/baiduseo/</guid><description>Introduction Baidu Webmaster Tools, or Baidu Ziyuan, is a resource platform that tracks and enhances your site’s organic performance on Baidu, China’s #1 search engine with 222+ million active users.
In addition to enabling faster mobile indexation on Baidu and improved monitoring of your site’s crawlability, Baidu Ziyuan (Baidu Webmaster Tools) identifies and recommends critical SEO best practices and solutions unique to your site to improve your visibility on the most-used search engine in China: Baidu.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started Org-mode on Emacs</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/org-mode/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 11:29:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/org-mode/</guid><description>Introduction Org mode is an artifact under Emacs. Compared with the lightweight format of markdown, It has more functions and expandability, but it is still difficult to get started. Here is only a brief introduction to some of the basic functions.
Pre-reading Emacs/Getting Started with Doom Emacs :Emacs:Doom-Emacs: Fundamental Feature Headings org-mode uses * to indicate headings, and the number of * to indicate heading level:
1 2 3 * First level heading ** Secondary heading *** Level 3 heading Use the Control-[RET] key to insert the title of the same level, and you can use the Alt-left/right title to increase and decrease the level Using Alt-Up and Alt-Down swap the Headings content Up and Down (including sub-chapters).</description></item><item><title>Creating a Hugo blog</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/hugo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 17:31:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/hugo/</guid><description>Overview This is a tutorial on creating a blog or website using hugo (a static site generator).
We will use Docker as our development environment. Also, we will storge our Hugo development code in Github main branche and automate the whole process with Github Action Workflow for Github Pages.
Prerequisites You will need to have the following:
Docker installation. Docker is available for Mac/Windows/Linux and is easily installed. You can following the link at the below for install Docker.</description></item></channel></rss>