<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>All Posts - Boyang Yan's Tech Blog</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/posts/</link><description>All Posts | Boyang Yan's Tech Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</managingEditor><webMaster>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 13:50:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yanboyang.com/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Getting Started Slock</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/slock/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 13:50:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/slock/</guid><description><![CDATA[Introduction slock Simple X display locker. This is the simplest X screen locker we are aware of.
1 2  git clone https://git.suckless.org/slock cd slock   Before, your sudo make install You need
1  vim config.def.h   change to
1 2 3  /* user and group to drop privileges to */ static const char *user = &#34;yanboyang713&#34;; static const char *group = &#34;yanboyang713&#34;;   slock: getgrnam nogroup: group entry not found]]></description></item><item><title>How to management patches in DWM</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/dwmpatches/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 13:50:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/dwmpatches/</guid><description>Introduction DWM only have less than 2000 lines of code. If you want to add more functionality for your DWM you need patches.
There are two types of patches:
The ones that fit to your personal taste The ones you think should be included in mainline. There are also have TWO patch methods.
Manual patches Using DWM Flexipatch (recommend) Pre-reading WM/Getting Started Dynamic Window Manager (DWM) Manual patches patch filename format The expected format for patches is:</description></item><item><title>Create Github Profile based on README</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/githubprofile/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 11:52:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/githubprofile/</guid><description>Introduction If you visit other peoples GitHub profiles, some people have some fancy pictures, descriptions and stats in their profiles. These are the new GitHub Profile README. They are kind of a hidden new feature and in this article I will show you how to create one and how make it stand out using some cool tricks and tools!
First Step: Crate new Github repository You should create a new repository, which name should same as your GitHub&amp;rsquo;s Username.</description></item><item><title>An introduction for Git</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/git/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 12:09:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/git/</guid><description>Git Cli Install If you facing this ERROR message (bash: gh: command not found), please following this document installing gh on your Linux first. Below section, I will tell you how to use Make to management your package.
1 sudo pacman -S github-cli Login Step1:
1 2 3 4 [yanboyang713@Boyang-PC dotfiles]$ gh auth login ? What account do you want to log into? [Use arrows to move, type to filter] &amp;gt; GitHub.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started Rofi</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/rofi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 17:41:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/rofi/</guid><description>Introduction Rofi is a window switcher, run dialog, ssh-launcher and dmenu replacement that started as a clone of simpleswitcher.
Installation First, Make sure you have the same (stable) version of rofi installed.
On Arch / Arch-based:
1 pacman -S rofi On Debian / Ubuntu:
1 apt-get install rofi On Fedora:
1 dnf install rofi Clone this repository</description></item><item><title>Getting Started NetworkManager</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/networkmanager/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 14:23:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/networkmanager/</guid><description>Introduction NetworkManager is the standard Linux network configuration tool suite. It supports large range of networking setups, from desktop to servers and mobile and integrates well with popular desktop environments and server configuration management tools.
It providing detection and configuration for systems to automatically connect to networks. NetworkManager&amp;rsquo;s functionality can be useful for both wireless and wired networks.
For wireless networks, NetworkManager prefers known wireless networks and has the ability to switch to the most reliable network.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started with NeoVim</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/neovim/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 18:36:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/neovim/</guid><description>What is NeoVim? If you are a system administrator or a software developer, a robust text editor is among the tools you use on a daily basis. It’s likely that you’ve used the vi or vim editors that have served the Unix and Linux communities for decades.
Although vim is under active development, it includes some ~300k lines of C89 code. In addition to being difficult to maintain, issues and new pull requests cannot be addressed very easily since Bram Moolenaar is the only person who maintains the large codebase of the program.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started Alacritty Terminal</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/alacritty/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 18:37:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/alacritty/</guid><description>Introduction Alacritty is a modern terminal emulator that comes with sensible defaults, but allows for extensive configuration. By integrating with other applications, rather than reimplementing their functionality, it manages to provide a flexible set of features with high performance. The supported platforms currently consist of BSD, Linux, macOS and Windows.
Installation NIX You can use NIX install Alacritty. Nix/Getting Started with Nix
Arch Linux 1 yay -S mesa-git alacritty-git Set as default terminal Ubuntu it is necessary to define it as an alternative available for ‘terminal’ type applications:</description></item><item><title>Take a Screenshot and upload to Cloudinary using Bash Scripts</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/cloudinary/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 16:12:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/cloudinary/</guid><description>Introduction In this article, I will introduce HOW TO take a screenshot and upload screenshot to cloudinary. Cloudinary will return the image URL and put it into your clipboard.
So, you can directly paste image URL using Control+v.
Cloudinary is an amazing image hosting service. We can upload all of our published image to WWW and save our local disk memory. Let&amp;rsquo;s we do it now!
Pre-reading Linux/Pipe to/from the clipboard in a Bash script Linux/Managing Your Dotfiles With Git and Make Pre-installion maim: take screenshots tool xclip: clipboard Python &amp;gt;= 3.</description></item><item><title>Pipe to/from the clipboard in a Bash script</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/clipboard/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 12:09:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/clipboard/</guid><description>Introduction The clipboard is a buffer that operating systems provide for short-term storage and transfer within and between application programs.
The clipboard provides an application programming interface by which programs can specify cut, copy and paste operations.
In the Post, I will introduct how to using xclip in Bash Script.
Installion Linux 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 # You can install xclip using `apt-get` apt-get install xclip # or `pacman` pacman -S xclip # or `dnf` dnf install xclip Set-up Bash In ~/.</description></item></channel></rss>