<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>org - Tag - Boyang Yan's Tech Blog</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/tags/org/</link><description>org - Tag - Boyang Yan's Tech Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</managingEditor><webMaster>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 15:08:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yanboyang.com/tags/org/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Getting Started with Org Roam</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/orgroam/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 15:08:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/orgroam/</guid><description>Set-up org roam</description></item><item><title>Using Emacs Org-Babel Mode to Write Literate Programming Documents</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/orgbabel/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 10:29:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/orgbabel/</guid><description>Introduction We introduce the use of emacs org-babel model in this document. Emacs Org-Babel mode is a literate programming tool (aka. active document), which can embed multiple programming languages, inlcuding R, Python, C/C++ in one document. Babel has ability to execute source code within Org-mode documents.
Pre-reading Emacs/Getting Started Org-mode on Emacs Source Code Insert &amp;amp; Running Here is an format example:
1 2 #+BEGIN_SRC language #+END_SRC Reference List https://orgmode.</description></item><item><title>Best practices for using Emacs org-mode as a day-planner/scheduler/calendar</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/orgplanning/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 18:28:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/orgplanning/</guid><description>Pre-reading Emacs/Getting Started Org-mode on Emacs Checkbox It often great to split a task into a number of simple steps. Or you can use them in a shopping list.
The form is [], put in front of the task can mark the completion status of the task, Put it after the task to mark the completion degree of the task, which needs to add % or /
Here is an example of a checkbox list.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started Org-mode on Emacs</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/org-mode/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 11:29:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/org-mode/</guid><description>Introduction Org mode is an artifact under Emacs. Compared with the lightweight format of markdown, It has more functions and expandability, but it is still difficult to get started. Here is only a brief introduction to some of the basic functions.
Pre-reading Emacs/Getting Started with Doom Emacs :Emacs:Doom-Emacs: Fundamental Feature Headings org-mode uses * to indicate headings, and the number of * to indicate heading level:
1 2 3 * First level heading ** Secondary heading *** Level 3 heading Use the Control-[RET] key to insert the title of the same level, and you can use the Alt-left/right title to increase and decrease the level Using Alt-Up and Alt-Down swap the Headings content Up and Down (including sub-chapters).</description></item><item><title>Building a Second Brain</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/secondbrain/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 10:18:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/secondbrain/</guid><description>Introduction Building a Second Brain is about creating a reliable system – outside your physical skin-and-bone bodily boundaries – for storing, organising, digesting, and eventually transforming information into Good Creative Output.
Much like any well-integrated tool, I am currently using Emacs Org Mode as Second Brain core tool. This system also includes many other peripheral components that make up the complete Second Brain system.
I will follow the below overview diagram introducte each components one by one.</description></item></channel></rss>