<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Ansible - Tag - Boyang Yan's Tech Blog</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/tags/ansible/</link><description>Ansible - Tag - Boyang Yan's Tech Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</managingEditor><webMaster>yanboyang713@gmail.com (Boyang Yan)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 17:58:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yanboyang.com/tags/ansible/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ansible Beginner's Guide</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/ansible/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 17:58:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/ansible/</guid><description>Overview This article covers all the aspects of Ansible, a tool used in DevOps for the Management, Deployment, and Orchestration of IT Infrastructure.
What Is Ansible? Ansible is a simple configuration management and IT automation engine for multi-tier deployments. It automates both cloud and on-premise provisioning &amp;amp; configuration. It automates cloud provisioning. Rather than managing one system at a time, Ansible uses a model that inter-relates the entire IT infrastructure and enables you to manage everything using something called an Infrastructure as Code (IAC) approach.</description></item><item><title>The comparison and introduction between Terraform and Ansible</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/terraformandansible/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 10:53:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/terraformandansible/</guid><description>Overview The Terraform vs. Ansible battle continues to escalate as the DevOps environment focuses more on automation and orchestration. These two tools help in automating configurations and deploying infrastructure. Terraform offers to deploy Infrastructure as a Code, helps in readability and lift and shift deployments. Ansible is a configuration management tool for automating system configuration and management.
Terraform What is Terraform? Terraform is an open-source tool for building, changing, and versioning infrastructure securely and effectively.</description></item><item><title>Build a Kubernetes cluster on Proxmox via Ansible and Terraform</title><link>https://yanboyang.com/k8sonproxmox/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 20:27:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://yanboyang.com/k8sonproxmox/</guid><description>Overview Proxmox is an open-source hypervisor that have enterprise capabilities and a large community behind it.
For Terraform and Ansible, I always like the idea of infrastructure as code (iac) and Terraform and Ansible just make it easy to accomplish.
The idea here was to be able to spin up a k3s cluster with minimum effort so I can spin it up and down for ever project that I would like to run.</description></item></channel></rss>